<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>security on Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in security on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maclaren.dev/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Seeing Red (Team)</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-09/seeing_red/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-09/seeing_red/</guid><description>Another change!? Jeez, how often do I change jobs? Seems like a lot, but it really isn&amp;rsquo;t. I&amp;rsquo;m still at the same company, I&amp;rsquo;ve just moved to a different team, and that&amp;rsquo;s after nearly 2 1/2 years in the my last role.
So what am I doing&amp;hellip;?
The best defense is a good offense My jersey has changed colours from blue to red! That&amp;rsquo;s right, I managed to social engineer our Red Team into thinking I&amp;rsquo;m the right person to join their team and enhance their capabilities.</description></item><item><title>DEFCON 32 - Very ENGAGING</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-08/defcon32/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-08/defcon32/</guid><description>Another year in ~hell~ Vegas We were back under one roof this year, which was such a nice change. For 30 and 31 I spent more time walking between talks/buildings than I did actually in the conference, to the point that I missed most if not all of the talks I wanted to see at 31. Not this year!
Relevant to work, this year also saw the debut of the Bug Bounty village.</description></item><item><title>NorthSec 2024 (FeetSec 2024?)</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-05/nsec_2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-05/nsec_2024/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get this out of the way NorthSec has nothing to do with feet, but somehow that became the theme this year thanks due to something getting lost in translation during an event. If you know, you know. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, then I guess you&amp;rsquo;ll have to come to the event in the future and find out!
gr33tz to team feetfeetfeetsec
I wish the NorthSec conference wasn&amp;rsquo;t only two days The amount of outstanding content, workshops, and side quests that NorthSec offers is just too much for only two days.</description></item><item><title>Cooking up some more CVEs</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-04/mealie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-04/mealie/</guid><description>Unlike state secrets, I don&amp;rsquo;t want my brisket recipes to wind up in a Florida bathroom As a follow up to the last time I wrote about CVEs, I&amp;rsquo;ve amassed a few more to my name:
CVE-2024-29191 CVE-2024-29192 CVE-2024-29193 CVE-2024-31991 CVE-2024-31992 CVE-2024-31993 CVE-2024-31994 The first three of these are related to go2rtc and are follow-ups from the earlier investigation done with Frigate. These were found in collaboration with Jorge Rosillo from GitHub Security Lab, and I recommend taking a read through the advisory article for details on these.</description></item></channel></rss>