<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>life on Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in life on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maclaren.dev/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DEFCON 30 - Homecoming</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-08/defcon30/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-08/defcon30/</guid><description>At last, DEFCON&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to go to DEFCON since I first heard about it almost 20 years ago, and finally the stars aligned and it was a possibility this year. Spoilers, it didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint.
While DEFCON is no longer the insane party that you may have heard of in the past, it&amp;rsquo;s none the less three-ish days of discovery and debauchery. Everything from super in-depth talks, to scavenger hunterse, to impromptu analog synth parties in the back end of the venue last at night after most folks have gone to bed.</description></item><item><title>Management, burnout, and upcoming changes</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-06/changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-06/changes/</guid><description>Management I got into management about a year ago, and it has been one hell of a ride. There&amp;rsquo;s sort of a running joke that &amp;ldquo;management isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone&amp;rdquo;, and I can certainly verify that.
I had moved into management with the hopes of it being a great way to advance my career further, push me closer to the goal of getting a Director position, and hopefully scratching the same problem solving itch that solving technical problems and helping organize my team as a lead did.</description></item></channel></rss>