<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maclaren.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is Support actually a dead-end?</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-02/deadend/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2024-02/deadend/</guid><description>Career laddering in Support I saw a really interesting post on LinkedIn the other day from Brian Levine talking about how support is a &amp;ldquo;dead-end&amp;rdquo; job.
The premise of his article was effectively that in many companies Support is often seen as entry level, with no possible advancement in the organization outside of management. While his proposal discusses laddering up to &amp;ldquo;Senior&amp;rdquo; positions, I find that this may be aiming too low when looking at deeply technical support work like with many &amp;ldquo;enterprise&amp;rdquo; products.</description></item><item><title>State of the Lab (late 2023)</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-12/lab_updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-12/lab_updates/</guid><description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t you just blog that this was going to be a 2024 project? Or, more specifically, I got a bit too excited after writing the last post and some hardware I was eyeing up went on sale. Since this update is happening today (hopefully) I figured this might be a good time to finally do a full walkthrough of what hardware and services I&amp;rsquo;m running.
The hardware Old &amp;amp; busted As noted, I&amp;rsquo;m finally replacing my venerable home server.</description></item><item><title>2023 in Review - DEFCON, CVEs, and Life</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-12/2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-12/2023/</guid><description>What is time, anyway? 2023 is at an end, and my posts to this blog have been few and far between this year. Fortunately, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a reflection of having a lack of things to do but perhaps the opposite. Please enjoy this highlight reel of &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; things that 2023 has brought&amp;hellip;
I spoke at a few conferences One of my personal goals this year was to submit to a few CFPs (Call for Papers) for various security-related conferences after getting back into public speaking in some capacity with BSides Ottawa in 2022.</description></item><item><title>NorthSec 2023 - A LAN party for hackers</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-05/nsec2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-05/nsec2023/</guid><description>What is NorthSec? NorthSec is a security conference in Montreal, QC, Canada that has been running since 2013. In addition to fantastic technical talks, awesome badges, and free beer (yes, really), they have one of the largest in-person CTF events on earth.
This year&amp;rsquo;s event saw ~1,500 attendees for the conference/talks, and 700+ for the in-person CTF event.
Somewhat unique, at least in my conference experience, much of the content in the talks at North Sec is highly technical.</description></item><item><title>CyberApocalypse 2023 - A CTF Competition</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-03/capturing_some_flags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-03/capturing_some_flags/</guid><description>Another month, another CTF event HackTheBox runs a large, free, CTF event every year called CyberApocalypse. These events tend to have a theme, though it&amp;rsquo;s largely irrelevant to the actual challenges (or often their content), however it creates a fun little narrative to go along with it and sometimes gives contextual clues.
I participated again this year with a bit of a rag-tag crew from my work, and it was fun as usual.</description></item><item><title>Remote Work Tips &amp; Tricks</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-03/remote_work_tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-03/remote_work_tips/</guid><description>Overview Over the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve been having conversations with folks who have started working remotely out of necessity, rather than choice. Obviously there are a ton of factors that play into this, not the least of which has been COVID, however historically this tended to be something that folks would actively seek out as a niche rather than a wide-spread go-to.
While there has been no shortage of content written on this topic with tips &amp;amp; tricks around WFH/remote work, it generally feels like few of these are from folks who have been doing this long term.</description></item><item><title>March Madness</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-03/march_madness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-03/march_madness/</guid><description>Happy pi day!
It has been a minute As someone working in the tech industry right now, let&amp;rsquo;s just say I haven&amp;rsquo;t been in the best frame of mind to blog about stuff, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few ideas for some content here, so maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll all flow out at once 🤷 On an immediately bright note, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been laid off (yet), so things continue to look up!
With that said, this article is going to be upbeat!</description></item><item><title>January's woes</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-01/january_woes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-01/january_woes/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s ~Morphin~ Bitchin time! I try to stay pretty positive with this blog, so I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this reasonably short.
The Apple Silicon Macs are amazing performance, battery life, power consumption, etc&amp;hellip; They&amp;rsquo;re also nearly worthless for my usecase as a developer and user of predominantly x86 applications.
Fortunately, most of the Python ecosystem seems to support aarch64 so much of my code works. The problems in Python come when you need something that&amp;rsquo;s x86 native&amp;hellip; like trying to use pwntools.</description></item><item><title>Obligatory look back at 2022</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-12/make_a_ctf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-12/make_a_ctf/</guid><description>In retrospect&amp;hellip; Certainly there has been a fair bit of change for me over the course of 2022. I&amp;hellip;
Found a new hobby (CTF) and continue to build those skills Realized being a people manager wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me Have been involved in tons of engineering projects that I otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a chance to work on Changed career paths (within tech) pretty drastically Joined a great team and have seen its members grow significantly Am exploring multiple new and exciting career and learning opportunities Went on a trip to DEFCON, something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do for many years Spoke at a security conference, and have submitted to the CFP for others!</description></item><item><title>Bare metal</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/baremetal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/baremetal/</guid><description>Vacations are dangerous I decided to take about a week and a half off to decompress, and it has been a fair bit more productive than I expected it to be given that the plan was to do nothing&amp;hellip;
I thought to myself:
Hey Logan, you&amp;rsquo;ve got nothing going on for the next few days, and could afford to do some firefighting if needed&amp;hellip; Why don&amp;rsquo;t you do a bare metal Arch install on your main rig?</description></item></channel></rss>