<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maclarel.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HackTheBox - Cyber Apocalypse 2022</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-05/htb_cyber_apolcalypse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-05/htb_cyber_apolcalypse/</guid><description>Well, that was harder than expected Many times in life it&amp;rsquo;s great to have a humbling experience. Not that I had an ego in this space anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m super new to it, but I was going in expecting to be able to crank through a fair number of challenges for this event. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say that didn&amp;rsquo;t happen.
Cyber Apocalypse 2022 was a jeopardy style CTF event with categories across all of the usual HackTheBox challenge content.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Strike CTF 2022 - Contoso Financial</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/msft_contoso_strike/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/msft_contoso_strike/</guid><description>Premise Microsoft runs an internal CTF event every so often called Strike CTF. While we&amp;rsquo;ve been asked not to share specifics around the challenges involved, I wanted to do a brief write-up, as it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a unique one that catered to multiple skill levels and had an educational twist.
For anyone interested in doing some digging, the version Microsoft runs has also been seen in some B-Sides events (and other conferences) under the name ShadowBank.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - Pandora</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/htb_pandora/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/htb_pandora/</guid><description>Premise Second verse same as the first - we&amp;rsquo;re given an IP and no further information. Commence enumeration!
Enumeration To set the stage, enumeration is probably the hardest part of this challenge. The rest is doable with some patience and research.
Out of the gate we have a website talking about some random product. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing interactable, and nmap only gives us TCP 22 and 80 as open ports.
Fuzzing with ffuf and nikto turns up nothing actionable, just icons and asset directories, neither of which can be used for anything.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - Paper</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/htb_paper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/htb_paper/</guid><description>Premise As with all Hack The Box (HTB) Machines we&amp;rsquo;re given nothing more than an IP.
Initial target enumeration with nmap shows us TCP 22, 80, and 443 open, with SSH and Apache 2.4.37 respectively. The TLS information returned isn&amp;rsquo;t super helpful, and hitting the website gives us nothing more than the default CentOS Apache httpd page.
Further exploration Next step, after a lot of poking, prodding, fuzzing, etc&amp;hellip; and getting nowhere was to try out nikto to see if there&amp;rsquo;s anything else the webserver might be leaking for us.</description></item><item><title>picoCTF - notepad</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-03/pico_notepad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-03/pico_notepad/</guid><description>Premise We&amp;rsquo;re given a service that will take abitrary input, and render it as an HTML page.
There are a few restrictions:
Content cannot be longer than 512 characters Content cannot include _ or / characters Lastly, from the Dockerfile we know that the flag is going to have an arbtirary name starting with flag-.
Examining the tarball This challenge comes with a tarball that contains the source code so we can do some white box analysis of how all of this works.</description></item><item><title>Home lab updates v2</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/home_lab_updates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/home_lab_updates/</guid><description>Looks like the last time I posted any updates about my home lab setup was back in April of 2020, so I guess we&amp;rsquo;re do for an update!
What has changed? Server rebuild New (2nd hand) 24 port gigabit switch 900W UPS Synology DS918 NAS So what am I doing with all these toys? The server rebuild is probably one of the bigger things here. While I was already hosting VMs and Docker containers on this box when it was running Windows, it was unreliable at best thanks to forced updates/reboots in Windows 10.</description></item><item><title>Publish articles with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/actions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/actions/</guid><description>Well, that was easier than expected. Take a look at peaceiris' actions-hugo repository for a workflow that can automate Hugo builds with all sorts of configurations.
I was expecting this project to take about an hour of tinkering, but it wound up taking under 5 minutes. Hooray!</description></item><item><title>I still use Arch, btw</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/still_use_arch/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/still_use_arch/</guid><description>Yep, the meme lives on. Still getting by with Arch as a daily driver. Still running it through VirtualBox.
What&amp;rsquo;s great? Full control, and amazingly lightweight. Booted, and with my WM (i3) running, I&amp;rsquo;m measuring &amp;lt; 300MB of RAM usage and virtually zero CPU/disk usage. Windows or Mac OS sitting idle&amp;hellip; yeah, not comparable. Itg&amp;rsquo;s very refreshing having full control over just about every aspect of what I want.
I&amp;rsquo;m getting so used to using i3, with only extremly minor modifications to bindings, that I&amp;rsquo;ve actually updated a lot of my Amethyst bindings to align with i3 defaults.</description></item><item><title>Relentless follow-through in Support</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/expectations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/expectations/</guid><description>Way back in April 2020 I wrote an article called Written communication for support which covered some high level best practices around setting, managing, and resetting expectations. Think of this as a spiritual successor to that article, as we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about the other side of the coin - relentless follow-through.
To put &amp;ldquo;relentless follow-through&amp;rdquo; in more direct terms, I want to discuss some best practices around timeliness of responses even when there&amp;rsquo;s no news, internal follow-up and expectation setting, and some options for collaboration (depending on the size/maturity of your business).</description></item><item><title>I use Arch, btw</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-10/arch_btw/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-10/arch_btw/</guid><description>I use Arch, btw I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux for ages, nearly two decades at this point. I actually dug out my old Mandrake and Slackware CDs while going through a box in my basement the other day&amp;hellip; quite the flashback.
Despite that tenure on at least some of the hardware I&amp;rsquo;ve owned at any given time, I&amp;rsquo;ve never really used it as a daily driver for desktop usage. That changed today when I finally sat down and set up Arch, complete with forgetting to install a boot loader, on my main rig.</description></item></channel></rss>