<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maclaren.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>January's woes</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-01/january_woes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-01/january_woes/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s ~Morphin~ Bitchin time! I try to stay pretty positive with this blog, so I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this reasonably short.
The Apple Silicon Macs are amazing performance, battery life, power consumption, etc&amp;hellip; They&amp;rsquo;re also nearly worthless for my usecase as a developer and user of predominantly x86 applications.
Fortunately, most of the Python ecosystem seems to support aarch64 so much of my code works. The problems in Python come when you need something that&amp;rsquo;s x86 native&amp;hellip; like trying to use pwntools.</description></item><item><title>Obligatory look back at 2022</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-12/make_a_ctf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-12/make_a_ctf/</guid><description>In retrospect&amp;hellip; Certainly there has been a fair bit of change for me over the course of 2022. I&amp;hellip;
Found a new hobby (CTF) and continue to build those skills Realized being a people manager wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me Have been involved in tons of engineering projects that I otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a chance to work on Changed career paths (within tech) pretty drastically Joined a great team and have seen its members grow significantly Am exploring multiple new and exciting career and learning opportunities Went on a trip to DEFCON, something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do for many years Spoke at a security conference, and have submitted to the CFP for others!</description></item><item><title>Bare metal</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/baremetal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/baremetal/</guid><description>Vacations are dangerous I decided to take about a week and a half off to decompress, and it has been a fair bit more productive than I expected it to be given that the plan was to do nothing&amp;hellip;
I thought to myself:
Hey Logan, you&amp;rsquo;ve got nothing going on for the next few days, and could afford to do some firefighting if needed&amp;hellip; Why don&amp;rsquo;t you do a bare metal Arch install on your main rig?</description></item><item><title>Contributing to a CTF event</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/make_a_ctf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/make_a_ctf/</guid><description>The project I recently had the opportunity to join a team building out some challenges for the Ekoparty CTF event, as my company has been a sponsor for a number of years. Given that I&amp;rsquo;ve been reasonably involved in playing CTFs as of late, as well as helping organize events within my company, I figured it might be fun to try building some challenges as well!
I worked with two colleagues to put together a series of 4 challenges:</description></item><item><title>TryHackMe - Root Me</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-10/thm_rootme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-10/thm_rootme/</guid><description>Premise RootMe is an introductory machine challenge on TryHackMe where the player is presented with a Linux machine they must get access to. This article is written to be more of a guide than a challenge writeup, with the goal of helping newer CTF players accustomed to some of the tools and techniques used for these kinds of challenges.
Throughout this walkthrough you&amp;rsquo;ll see reference to $target which is just me storing the IP address of the target machine in an environment variable for easier reference and reuse.</description></item><item><title>HackTheBox - Trick</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/htb_trick/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/htb_trick/</guid><description>Premise Trick is machine challenge that presents itself initially as an incomplete website - from there we need to perform various types of enumeration, avoid rabbitholes, and use some classic vulnerabilities to get our flags!
Recon If we hit the challenge&amp;rsquo;s IP directly we get a totally non-functional website. There are initial references to a bootstrap form url (just https://startbootstrap/&amp;lt;stuff here&amp;gt;) however this will go nowhere - this is just poor documentation on the bootstrap side I think, as it should have .</description></item><item><title>Bell HomeHub 4000 + Ubiquiti Unifi Dream Machine VPN</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/bell_udm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/bell_udm/</guid><description>This article is a bit more to-the-point than most others I&amp;rsquo;ve written, and is mostly to serve as a reference point for others trying to configure a VPN server with Unifi products behind the Bell HomeHub 4000.
The HomeHub 4000 DMZ works&amp;hellip; kinda The HomeHub 4000 doesn&amp;rsquo;t have Bridge mode, period. This leaves users with three options:
Find a way to use PPPoE directly (possible, but janky) Use the &amp;ldquo;Advanced DMZ&amp;rdquo; feature on the HomeHub 4000 (Spoilers: It doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all) Use the normal DMZ feature on the HomeHub 4000 and deal with double-NAT After several days of troubleshooting I opted for option 3 from the list above.</description></item><item><title>Karabiner is a game changer</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/karabiner/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/karabiner/</guid><description>What is Karabiner and why? Karabiner Elements is an open source MacOS application that can be used to intercept and modify any keystroke, combination, etc&amp;hellip; on your machine and change it to do damn near anything you want. If you follow my blog or know me, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of custom keyboards and the flexibility that they allow by way of QMK or similar firmware - Karabiner recreates a lot of that functionality at the software level.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - RedPanda</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-08/htb_redpanda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-08/htb_redpanda/</guid><description>Premise RedPanda is a machine challenge that presents the attacker with a web app displaying cute pictures of Red Pandas. Adorable. The goal, as usual, is to find both user and root flags. This is done through a combination of SSTI and XXE, and admittedly is one of the most difficult challenges that I&amp;rsquo;ve completed so far&amp;hellip; despite being on the &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; end of the spectrum.
Notes in this writeup will be a bit more freeform than others as I think sharing the overall approach I took may be of interest.</description></item><item><title>DEFCON 30 - Homecoming</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-08/defcon30/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-08/defcon30/</guid><description>At last, DEFCON&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to go to DEFCON since I first heard about it almost 20 years ago, and finally the stars aligned and it was a possibility this year. Spoilers, it didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint.
While DEFCON is no longer the insane party that you may have heard of in the past, it&amp;rsquo;s none the less three-ish days of discovery and debauchery. Everything from super in-depth talks, to scavenger hunterse, to impromptu analog synth parties in the back end of the venue last at night after most folks have gone to bed.</description></item></channel></rss>