<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maclaren.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bare metal</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/baremetal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/baremetal/</guid><description>Vacations are dangerous I decided to take about a week and a half off to decompress, and it has been a fair bit more productive than I expected it to be given that the plan was to do nothing&amp;hellip;
I thought to myself:
Hey Logan, you&amp;rsquo;ve got nothing going on for the next few days, and could afford to do some firefighting if needed&amp;hellip; Why don&amp;rsquo;t you do a bare metal Arch install on your main rig?</description></item><item><title>Contributing to a CTF event</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/make_a_ctf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-11/make_a_ctf/</guid><description>The project I recently had the opportunity to join a team building out some challenges for the Ekoparty CTF event, as my company has been a sponsor for a number of years. Given that I&amp;rsquo;ve been reasonably involved in playing CTFs as of late, as well as helping organize events within my company, I figured it might be fun to try building some challenges as well!
I worked with two colleagues to put together a series of 4 challenges:</description></item><item><title>TryHackMe - Root Me</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-10/thm_rootme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-10/thm_rootme/</guid><description>Premise RootMe is an introductory machine challenge on TryHackMe where the player is presented with a Linux machine they must get access to. This article is written to be more of a guide than a challenge writeup, with the goal of helping newer CTF players accustomed to some of the tools and techniques used for these kinds of challenges.
Throughout this walkthrough you&amp;rsquo;ll see reference to $target which is just me storing the IP address of the target machine in an environment variable for easier reference and reuse.</description></item><item><title>Bell HomeHub 4000 + Ubiquiti Unifi Dream Machine VPN</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/bell_udm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/bell_udm/</guid><description>This article is a bit more to-the-point than most others I&amp;rsquo;ve written, and is mostly to serve as a reference point for others trying to configure a VPN server with Unifi products behind the Bell HomeHub 4000.
The HomeHub 4000 DMZ works&amp;hellip; kinda The HomeHub 4000 doesn&amp;rsquo;t have Bridge mode, period. This leaves users with three options:
Find a way to use PPPoE directly (possible, but janky) Use the &amp;ldquo;Advanced DMZ&amp;rdquo; feature on the HomeHub 4000 (Spoilers: It doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at all) Use the normal DMZ feature on the HomeHub 4000 and deal with double-NAT After several days of troubleshooting I opted for option 3 from the list above.</description></item><item><title>Karabiner is a game changer</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/karabiner/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-09/karabiner/</guid><description>What is Karabiner and why? Karabiner Elements is an open source MacOS application that can be used to intercept and modify any keystroke, combination, etc&amp;hellip; on your machine and change it to do damn near anything you want. If you follow my blog or know me, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of custom keyboards and the flexibility that they allow by way of QMK or similar firmware - Karabiner recreates a lot of that functionality at the software level.</description></item><item><title>DEFCON 30 - Homecoming</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-08/defcon30/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-08/defcon30/</guid><description>At last, DEFCON&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to go to DEFCON since I first heard about it almost 20 years ago, and finally the stars aligned and it was a possibility this year. Spoilers, it didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint.
While DEFCON is no longer the insane party that you may have heard of in the past, it&amp;rsquo;s none the less three-ish days of discovery and debauchery. Everything from super in-depth talks, to scavenger hunterse, to impromptu analog synth parties in the back end of the venue last at night after most folks have gone to bed.</description></item><item><title>Management, burnout, and upcoming changes</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-06/changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-06/changes/</guid><description>Management I got into management about a year ago, and it has been one hell of a ride. There&amp;rsquo;s sort of a running joke that &amp;ldquo;management isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone&amp;rdquo;, and I can certainly verify that.
I had moved into management with the hopes of it being a great way to advance my career further, push me closer to the goal of getting a Director position, and hopefully scratching the same problem solving itch that solving technical problems and helping organize my team as a lead did.</description></item><item><title>Ploopy Classic &amp; Nano Trackballs</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-06/ploopy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-06/ploopy/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s a silly name Yes.
What are they? Ploopy is a company that designs and produces open-source trackballs and mice.
Having been a Trackball enthusiast for a while, and not being able to find one that I really liked, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d give this a shot. One of my gripes in general has been that most of the trackballs out there are either great functionall but have shitty ergnomics, or have great ergonomics and awful functionality/drivers.</description></item><item><title>HackTheBox - Cyber Apocalypse 2022</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-05/htb_cyber_apolcalypse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-05/htb_cyber_apolcalypse/</guid><description>Well, that was harder than expected Many times in life it&amp;rsquo;s great to have a humbling experience. Not that I had an ego in this space anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m super new to it, but I was going in expecting to be able to crank through a fair number of challenges for this event. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say that didn&amp;rsquo;t happen.
Cyber Apocalypse 2022 was a jeopardy style CTF event with categories across all of the usual HackTheBox challenge content.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Strike CTF 2022 - Contoso Financial</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-04/msft_contoso_strike/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-04/msft_contoso_strike/</guid><description>Premise Microsoft runs an internal CTF event every so often called Strike CTF. While we&amp;rsquo;ve been asked not to share specifics around the challenges involved, I wanted to do a brief write-up, as it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a unique one that catered to multiple skill levels and had an educational twist.
For anyone interested in doing some digging, the version Microsoft runs has also been seen in some B-Sides events (and other conferences) under the name ShadowBank.</description></item></channel></rss>