<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>github on Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://maclaren.dev/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in github on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maclaren.dev/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publish articles with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://maclaren.dev/posts/2021-11/actions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclaren.dev/posts/2021-11/actions/</guid><description>Well, that was easier than expected. Take a look at peaceiris' actions-hugo repository for a workflow that can automate Hugo builds with all sorts of configurations.
I was expecting this project to take about an hour of tinkering, but it wound up taking under 5 minutes. Hooray!</description></item><item><title>Hello via GitHub Pages</title><link>https://maclaren.dev/posts/2021-01/github-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclaren.dev/posts/2021-01/github-pages/</guid><description>Well this is new&amp;hellip; Rather than dealing with Blogger, a dubious mobile interface, and spreading things across many services&amp;hellip; why not just use GitHub Pages? I&amp;rsquo;m so used to writing markdown at this point that it just seems easier 😄
Hugo Inspired by tmpdubz I figured I&amp;rsquo;d do a double-whammy here - play around with/learn GitHub Pages, while also giving my blog a much needed cosmetic overhaul/simplification/rebranding. This lead to Hugo, which is pretty darn neat.</description></item><item><title>Git &amp; GitHub Tutorial - Part 2 - Branching, forking, and pull requests</title><link>https://maclaren.dev/posts/2020-08/github-tutorial-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclaren.dev/posts/2020-08/github-tutorial-part-2/</guid><description>This is part 2 of a Git tutorial series - I recommend watching part 1 @ https://youtu.be/jhgoGnYgPuY first!
In this video we take a look at creating new branches in a Git repository, forking other repositories, and creating pull requests:</description></item><item><title>Git &amp; GitHub Tutorial - Part 1 - Creating &amp; using a Git repository</title><link>https://maclaren.dev/posts/2020-07/github-tutorial-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclaren.dev/posts/2020-07/github-tutorial-part-1/</guid><description>In this video we start to delve into using Git and GitHub to track a project. We will create a repository, clone it, make changes, and push those changes back up to GitHub so that everyone can view them!</description></item></channel></rss>