<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Logan MacLaren</title>
		<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Logan MacLaren</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://maclarel.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Hello via GitHub Pages</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-01/github-pages/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-01/github-pages/</guid>
			<description>Well this is new&amp;hellip; Rather than dealing with Blogger, a dubious mobile interface, and spreading things across many services&amp;hellip; why not just use GitHub Pages? I&amp;rsquo;m so used to writing markdown at this point that it just seems easier 😄
Hugo Inspired by tmpdubz I figured I&amp;rsquo;d do a double-whammy here - play around with/learn GitHub Pages, while also giving my blog a much needed cosmetic overhaul/simplification/rebranding. This lead to Hugo, which is pretty darn neat.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="well-this-is-new">Well this is new&hellip;</h1>
<p>Rather than dealing with Blogger, a dubious mobile interface, and spreading things across many services&hellip; why not just use GitHub Pages? I&rsquo;m so used to writing markdown at this point that it just seems easier 😄</p>
<h1 id="hugo">Hugo</h1>
<p>Inspired by <a href="https://github.com/tmpdubz">tmpdubz</a> I figured I&rsquo;d do a double-whammy here - play around with/learn GitHub Pages, while also giving my blog a much needed cosmetic overhaul/simplification/rebranding. This lead to <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a>, which is pretty darn neat.</p>
<p>Hugo is reasonably well documented, config driven, and quite intuitive to pick up and run with. Setting up this whole blog system on GitHub Pages took under 15 minutes (not including manually migrating blog content over).</p>
<p>Check it out if you&rsquo;re looking to throw together a simple site! You can check out what a finished project looks like by reviewing what&rsquo;s powering this very blog <a href="https://github.com/maclarel/maclarel.github.io">in my GitHub repo</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Git &amp; GitHub Tutorial - Part 2 - Branching, forking, and pull requests</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-08/github-tutorial-part-2/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-08/github-tutorial-part-2/</guid>
			<description>This is part 2 of a Git tutorial series - I recommend watching part 1 @ https://youtu.be/jhgoGnYgPuY first!
In this video we take a look at creating new branches in a Git repository, forking other repositories, and creating pull requests:</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is part 2 of a Git tutorial series - I recommend watching part 1 @ <a href="https://youtu.be/jhgoGnYgPuY">https://youtu.be/jhgoGnYgPuY</a> first!</p>
<p>In this video we take a look at creating new branches in a Git repository, forking other repositories, and creating pull requests:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V8vUYUvDSfY"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/V8vUYUvDSfY/0.jpg" alt="GitHub Tutorial - Part 2"></a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Git &amp; GitHub Tutorial - Part 1 - Creating &amp; using a Git repository</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/github-tutorial-part-1/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/github-tutorial-part-1/</guid>
			<description>In this video we start to delve into using Git and GitHub to track a project. We will create a repository, clone it, make changes, and push those changes back up to GitHub so that everyone can view them!</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this video we start to delve into using Git and GitHub to track a project. We will create a repository, clone it, make changes, and push those changes back up to GitHub so that everyone can view them!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jhgoGnYgPuY"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/jhgoGnYgPuY/0.jpg" alt="GitHub Tutorial - Part 1"></a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Key-based Authentication for SSH</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/key-based-auth-ssh/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/key-based-auth-ssh/</guid>
			<description>Tired of trying to remember passwords for every system you access, or annoyed that every system uses the same password? Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a more secure approach that can solve both problems - key based authentication with SSH!</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tired of trying to remember passwords for every system you access, or annoyed that every system uses the same password? Let&rsquo;s look at a more secure approach that can solve both problems - key based authentication with SSH!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tSqyTH_QS1I"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/tSqyTH_QS1I/0.jpg" alt="Key-based Auth Tutorial"></a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>SSH Port Forwarding</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/ssh-port-forwarding/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/ssh-port-forwarding/</guid>
			<description>Have a service that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to directly expose, or that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have good security, that you still need to access? Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at using SSH to accomplish this!
This tutorial uses nc, UFW/IPTables, and SSH to demonstrate how to forward any port over an SSH connection on TCP 22. You can extend this to just about any service. For example, this works for accessing websites, or other services that are exposed through a web browser.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have a service that you don&rsquo;t want to directly expose, or that doesn&rsquo;t have good security, that you still need to access? Today we&rsquo;re going to look at using SSH to accomplish this!</p>
<p>This tutorial uses <code>nc</code>, <code>UFW/IPTables</code>, and <code>SSH</code> to demonstrate how to forward any port over an SSH connection on TCP 22. You can extend this to just about any service. For example, this works for accessing websites, or other services that are exposed through a web browser.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hb80XpmLJ1U"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/hb80XpmLJ1U/0.jpg" alt="SSH Port Forwarding"></a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Home Office Tour</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/home-office-tour/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/home-office-tour/</guid>
			<description>A quick tour of my full time work-from-home office! I&amp;rsquo;ve been working remote for many years now, and for the past ~18 months I&amp;rsquo;ve been working from home almost exclusively (no more travel).
This is a quick look over the setup that I use every day!
Equipment shown:
 Desk: Jarvis Standing Desk Monitor: LG 38UC99-W Monitor Arm: Amazon Basics Premium Mouse: Logitech MX Master Keyboard: Das Keyboard 4C Professional (MX Brown) Laptop Stand: Rain Design mStand Dock: CalDigit TS3 Plus Chair: HÅG Capisco Puls Standing mat: Ergodriven Topo</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A quick tour of my full time work-from-home office! I&rsquo;ve been working remote for many years now, and for the past ~18 months I&rsquo;ve been working from home almost exclusively (no more travel).</p>
<p>This is a quick look over the setup that I use every day!</p>
<p>Equipment shown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Desk: Jarvis Standing Desk</li>
<li>Monitor: LG 38UC99-W</li>
<li>Monitor Arm: Amazon Basics Premium</li>
<li>Mouse: Logitech MX Master</li>
<li>Keyboard: Das Keyboard 4C Professional (MX Brown)</li>
<li>Laptop Stand: Rain Design mStand</li>
<li>Dock: CalDigit TS3 Plus</li>
<li>Chair: HÅG Capisco Puls</li>
<li>Standing mat: Ergodriven Topo</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=blZYivfDoDs"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/blZYivfDoDs/0.jpg" alt="Home Office Walkthrough"></a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Home lab updates</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</guid>
			<description>Following up from my &amp;ldquo;Starting out with a home lab&amp;rdquo; article I&amp;rsquo;ve made some pretty nice updates to my home lab setup, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also got my {Ansible playbooks](https://github.com/maclarel/ansible_playbooks) up on GitHub now!
Starting out with the lab additions:
 Gigabit internet (Cable, unfortunately) recently became available here, so I&amp;rsquo;ve now got a 1000/30 connection! Upload speeds are depressing, but still 3x the speed I had previously! UniFi Dream Machine has taken over my network.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following up from my &ldquo;Starting out with a home lab&rdquo; article I&rsquo;ve made some pretty nice updates to my home lab setup, and I&rsquo;ve also got my {Ansible playbooks](<a href="https://github.com/maclarel/ansible_playbooks">https://github.com/maclarel/ansible_playbooks</a>) up on GitHub now!</p>
<p>Starting out with the lab additions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Gigabit internet (Cable, unfortunately) recently became available here, so I&rsquo;ve now got a 1000/30 connection! Upload speeds are depressing, but still 3x the speed I had previously!</li>
<li><a href="https://store.ui.com/collections/unifi-network-routing-switching/products/unifi-dream-machine">UniFi Dream Machine</a> has taken over my network. This thing is literally stepping forward 15 years in terms of technology over what I was previously using&hellip;</li>
<li><a href="https://store.ui.com/collections/wireless/products/unifi-nanohd-us?_pos=1&amp;_sid=b2cf06452&amp;_ss=r">UniFi NanoHD Access Point</a> for improved network connectivity on the second floor of my house. Dramatic improvement in connection quality!
And perhaps most importantly, the whole layout is now more A E S T H E T I C&hellip;</li>
</ul>
<p>Before:</p>
<p><img src="https://i.redd.it/wbluzsg4nvt41.jpg" alt="oldandbusted"></p>
<p>After:</p>
<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/1tjFzgF.jpg" alt="newhotness"></p>
<p>Significant improvements all around!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Written communication for support</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/written-communication-for-support/</link>
			<pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/written-communication-for-support/</guid>
			<description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in customer facing roles for quite a while now. Granted, these have largely had the luxury of being in software companies, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also done a brief retail stint and I&amp;rsquo;d like to think the same skills apply in all cases.
While this will be by no means exhaustive, I want to go over two high-level concepts that I feel are extremely important, and can sometimes be overlooked even by veterans in customer facing positions.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been working in customer facing roles for quite a while now. Granted, these have largely had the luxury of being in software companies, but I&rsquo;ve also done a brief retail stint and I&rsquo;d like to think the same skills apply in all cases.</p>
<p>While this will be by no means exhaustive, I want to go over two high-level concepts that I feel are extremely important, and can sometimes be overlooked even by veterans in customer facing positions.</p>
<h1 id="managing-expectations">Managing Expectations</h1>
<p>This may sound simple, and it is a straight forward concept, but it&rsquo;s all too oft ignored. We&rsquo;ll dive into some examples below as to how easy it is to really nail this and create a great customer experience.</p>
<h2 id="setting-expectations">Setting Expectations</h2>
<p>Have you ever received this email when working with a company?</p>
<pre><code>Hi &lt;Name&gt;,

Thanks for reaching out for assistance!

We understand that you're encountering problem &lt;X&gt; which is blocking your work. Thanks so much for providing the steps to reproduce this problem! I'll see if I can reproduce this problem here, and will be in touch.

Regards,
&lt;Friendly Support Person&gt;
</code></pre><p>Hmmmm&hellip; What&rsquo;s wrong here?</p>
<ul>
<li>The person asking for help is politely acknowledged and greeted.</li>
<li>The problem is restarted for clarity, including acknowledging the severity of the issue.</li>
<li>The reproducible testcase is acknowledged.</li>
<li>Next steps are specified.</li>
<li>There&rsquo;s a friendly closing.</li>
</ul>
<p>Can&rsquo;t put your finger on it? There&rsquo;s no timeline associated with the next steps!</p>
<p>This seems pretty minor, but let&rsquo;s flesh this scenario out a little bit, and let&rsquo;s say that I&rsquo;m the person asking for assistance. I&rsquo;ve clearly run into a problem and it&rsquo;s significant enough that I&rsquo;ve taken the time to send in a request for assistance because I can&rsquo;t progress on my work. It&rsquo;s wonderful that I&rsquo;ve reached someone willing to help, and that they understand the problem at a high enough level to paraphrase it, but now I&rsquo;m left with absolutely no understanding of when I&rsquo;ll hear back.</p>
<p>You may be reading this and think that the next steps are solely with the person troubleshooting the problem on the Support side, but you&rsquo;d be partially wrong. With no firm timeline established, the affected user who submitted the ticket also has to proactively reach out to Support if they need an update, since they don&rsquo;t know when they&rsquo;ll hear back. This makes for a poor customer experience since they&rsquo;re left wondering if they&rsquo;re going to hear back in an hour, a day, a week, or never.</p>
<p>All to often I&rsquo;ll see this scenario play out, even with industry veterans, and almost without fail the very next entry in the ticket (regardless of timeline) is from the customer saying &ldquo;Any updates?&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s do a small tweak, and outline the impact it has:</p>
<pre><code>Hi &lt;Name&gt;,

Thanks for reaching out for assistance!

We understand that you're encountering problem &lt;X&gt; which is blocking your work. Thanks so much for providing the steps to reproduce this problem! I'll see if I can reproduce this problem here, and will provide you with an update by close of business tomorrow. 

Regards,
&lt;Friendly Support Person&gt;
</code></pre><p>All we&rsquo;ve done here is provide a timeline of getting a response by the end of the following day, but let&rsquo;s dive into what that entails:</p>
<ul>
<li>The customer now knows when they&rsquo;ll receive next contact, so they know they don&rsquo;t need to follow up before then unless something changes.</li>
<li>This gives the customer a clear path to update the ticket owner on changing priorities. For example, is this actually blocking their whole team and not just them? Is there a business critical function that needs to happen by the end of the same day, meaning tomorrow is too late?</li>
<li>The ticket owner now has an obligation to address the issue on the timeline they&rsquo;ve specified, meaning they can better prioritize, instead of just throwing the issue into their (potentially large) backlog.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="resetting-expectations">Resetting Expectations</h2>
<p>In a perfect world, the severity of the problem in the example above was well communicated and ticket owner would provide a material update before the close of business the following day. Great, case closed (or at least notably progressed), but we all know that&rsquo;s not always what happens.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about resetting expectations that were set.</p>
<p>Things change. The customer who submitted that example ticket isn&rsquo;t the only person having problems. Let&rsquo;s assume for a moment that the ticket owner got hit with a much more important problem - like another customer being completely down and blocked - and they haven&rsquo;t had time to address our example problem.</p>
<p>There are two likely scenarios, and outcomes, of this.</p>
<h3 id="scenario-1----the-ticket-does-not-receive-an-update-before-close-of-business-the-following-day">Scenario 1 -  The ticket does not receive an update before close of business the following day</h3>
<p>This is the most common scenario I see from less experienced folks. Unfortunately, it tends to drive a far more negative outcome than you may expect at face value. Fortunately, it&rsquo;s a very easy problem to address!</p>
<p>Having dealt with customers as a front-line customer support person, an escalation point, a team lead, a main point-of-contact, and as a direct customer advocate, for almost 14 years I can quite comfortably tell you that the #1 cause of customer frustration is not receiving timely updates.</p>
<p>In this case, the customer is left without any information as to the status of their request and feels ignored. It&rsquo;s a safe bet that (assuming they haven&rsquo;t given up) that ticket owner is going to come in the next morning and see &ldquo;Any updates?&rdquo; front and center on that ticket. The customer won&rsquo;t be happy.</p>
<h3 id="scenario-2---the-ticket-is-updated-before-the-close-of-business-the-following-day-saying-that-theres-no-progress">Scenario 2 - The ticket is updated before the close of business the following day saying that there&rsquo;s no progress</h3>
<p>Prior to the end of the following day, the ticket owner sends off this update:</p>
<pre><code>Hi &lt;Name&gt;,

I just wanted to send you an update to note that I'm still looking into this here. I'll be in touch ASAP with next steps.

Regards,
&lt;Friendly Support Person&gt;
</code></pre><p>We&rsquo;re making progress with this, but still not perfect! Let&rsquo;s take a look at Scenario 3 for how we can reliable salvage this.</p>
<h3 id="scenario-3---the-ticket-is-updated-and-expectations-are-reset">Scenario 3 - The ticket is updated, and expectations are reset</h3>
<p>All we&rsquo;re going to do here is a minor tweak to the wording above. This will let us reset expectations with the customer and keep the next steps entirely on the Support side (save for a possible escalation).</p>
<pre><code>Hi &lt;Name&gt;,

I just wanted to send you an update to note that I'm still looking into this here. I'll be looking into this first thing tomorrow morning and will provide you with an update by mid-day tomorrow.

Regards,
&lt;Friendly Support Person&gt;
</code></pre><p>The customer has been informed of the delay, understands the prioritization moving forward, and knows to expect an update at the discussed time. This, in general, will keep them happy!</p>
<h2 id="further-breakdown">Further breakdown</h2>
<p>Obviously there&rsquo;s nuance to this, but as discussed above this is the most common cause for ticket escalations and overall poor customer experience. Overall length of time to (successfully) close a ticket is a distant second in terms of drivers for negative customer satisfaction behind a lack of communication.</p>
<p>While this scenario can be intimidating, I&rsquo;ll also not that you&rsquo;re significantly less likely to get directly negative feedback from a customer when providing a wrong answer, as long as it&rsquo;s done in a timely fashion and leaves the door open for them to follow-up with you.</p>
<h1 id="professional-written-communication">Professional Written Communication</h1>
<p>I&rsquo;ll start out by noting that there&rsquo;s a difference between formal communication and professional communication. A lot of this will come down to the company that you&rsquo;re working with, and the &ldquo;voice&rdquo; that they are trying to present. For the sake of this section, we&rsquo;re not discussing formal writing as that&rsquo;s it&rsquo;s own skill in many cases.</p>
<p>To start out with, this is not intended to &ldquo;shame&rdquo; anyone who is not a native speaker of whatever language they are communicating in. English, in particular, is a disaster of a language and (in my opinion) it&rsquo;s reasonably ignorant to judge someone based on their grasp of a non-native language. If you fall into this bucket, I&rsquo;d strongly recommend the use of a Linter to help catch spelling and grammatical issues, such as linter-write-good for Atom.</p>
<p>With that out of the way, the high-level things we want to note here are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Organization of thoughts</li>
<li>Clear and concise wording</li>
<li>Proper punctuation, spelling, and grammar</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="organizing-your-thoughts">Organizing your Thoughts</h2>
<p>Issues can be complex, and responses can necessitate jumping between multiple logical scenarios. When you find yourself in this scenario, it can be very helpful to include things like headers (for example, the &ldquo;Organizing your Thoughts&rdquo; header here) to more clearly define context.</p>
<p>Similarly, it can be helpful to have a very high level summary, sometimes using bullet points or a numbered list, to specifically outline the information that will be further discussed&hellip; as we&rsquo;ve also done here.</p>
<p>Clear and Concise Wording</p>
<p>Time is valuable. If you can clearly, and politely, communicate a thought in two sentences instead of two paragraphs, do it. I&rsquo;ll provide examples of good, and bad, responses below. We&rsquo;ll strip the pleasantries since we&rsquo;re just focusing on content.</p>
<h3 id="example-1">Example 1</h3>
<pre><code>I can see that in function findTheThing you've used a brute-force search across the array to find duplicate values. This type of approach is quite inefficient with large data sets.

You may want to consider loading values into a set for evaluation as this will likely perform much better.
</code></pre><h3 id="example-2">Example 2</h3>
<pre><code> I can see that in function findTheThing you've used a brute-force search across the array to find duplicate values. While a brute-force search is simple to implement, and will always find a solution if it exists, its cost is proportional to the number of candidate solutions – which in many practical problems tends to grow very quickly as the size of the problem increases 

You may want to consider loading values into a set for evaluation as this will likely perform much better. A set will allow you to only store the required values until a duplicate is found, which will likely result in significantly smaller memory utilization.
</code></pre><p>I&rsquo;ll note that both of these are completely valid responses that most customers would be happy to receive. In order to keep you, the reader of this article, paying attention I&rsquo;ve limited the verbosity that could have otherwise been included in <code>Example 2</code>.</p>
<p>At the end of the day here, you&rsquo;ll need to know your audience. In the example above, if it&rsquo;s safe to assume that your reader knows what a set is from a computer science perspective there&rsquo;s probably no need to explain how it should be implemented, or how it will differ from a brute-force search of an entire array.</p>
<h2 id="punctuation-spelling-and-grammar">Punctuation, Spelling, and Grammar</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m not going to dive into whether or not you should use Oxford commas, or try to note that you need to ensure you have sentence structure that your 10th grade English teacher would give you an A+ on. The goal here is to be legible, avoid ambiguity, and avoid reader frustration.</p>
<ul>
<li>Use paragraphs to logically divide thoughts.</li>
<li>Avoid run-on sentences.</li>
<li>Know the difference between your/you&rsquo;re, its/it&rsquo;s, there/their/they&rsquo;re, etc.
<ul>
<li>Again, a Linter will help here if you&rsquo;re not a native English speaker.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Proof-read your messages.</li>
</ul>
<p>I&rsquo;ll paraphrase a message I received recently which I think is a prime example of how not to write something.</p>
<pre><code>Hi Logan,

Hope you are doing well,

I see you have a problem and I would be more than happy to help you fix this problem that you described in your original message.

Please can you send me the following information - what version you are using, what operating system you are using for example Windows or Mac, and what browser? These information's will help to resolve your issue more quickly so it would be very helpful if you can provide them quickly thanks!

Regards,
&lt;Name&gt;
</code></pre><p>I actually cringed when reading the message that inspired this&hellip; and while writing this. Can I understand what they need? Absolutely. Did I have to re-read this a few times to understand? You bet.</p>
<p>As a &ldquo;fun&rdquo; exercise, try rewriting this in the comments below and see if you can clean it up!</p>
<h1 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up</h1>
<p>I know that this all seems very basic, and it is, but it&rsquo;s the kind of thing where practice makes perfect. It&rsquo;s also very easy to get into bad habits like not proof-reading messages before sending or not providing enough information in responses. Experience certainly helps.</p>
<p>There are many other concepts we could discuss, and maybe they&rsquo;ll be done so in another post, but I&rsquo;ll leave you all with one final recommendation:</p>
<p>If you are providing someone with technical instructions, be sure to test the instructions first or specifically outline if they have not been tested. Nothing is worse than being on the receiving end of something that doesn&rsquo;t work at all when dealing with an &ldquo;expert&rdquo;. Mistakes certainly happen, but this one can generally be avoided pretty easily.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Starting out with a home lab</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/starting-out-with-a-home-lab/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/starting-out-with-a-home-lab/</guid>
			<description>Why do I want a home lab? While only you, the reader, can answer this, there are many reasons that I&amp;rsquo;ve build one out. I imagine your reasoning will be similar.
 There are things you want to have, or automate, that are simply obnoxious otherwise. You&amp;rsquo;ve got specific technologies that you want to explore without a full scale investment. You&amp;rsquo;re working toward certifications (or hands-on experience) with technologies that you want to be using for work.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-do-i-want-a-home-lab">Why do I want a home lab?</h1>
<p>While only you, the reader, can answer this, there are many reasons that I&rsquo;ve build one out. I imagine your reasoning will be similar.</p>
<ul>
<li>There are things you want to have, or automate, that are simply obnoxious otherwise.</li>
<li>You&rsquo;ve got specific technologies that you want to explore without a full scale investment.</li>
<li>You&rsquo;re working toward certifications (or hands-on experience) with technologies that you want to be using for work.</li>
</ul>
<p>Personally, I just want to tinker. I&rsquo;m very lucky to have access to all of the tooling I need for my day job through work. With that said, there&rsquo;s a lot that I want to play with outside of that scope as well as many &ldquo;quality of life&rdquo; improvements that I want for my home network such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ad-blocking</li>
<li>In-home media storage &amp; streaming</li>
<li>On-site Backups</li>
<li>Home &amp; network security</li>
<li>Tinkering and learning</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="but-i-dont-have-a-server">But I don&rsquo;t have a server!</h1>
<p>The biggest misconception that people have about setting up a home lab is that they need to run out and buy a used Dell R710 (or something similar), load it with hard drives, and install <a href="https://www.proxmox.com/">Proxmox</a> or <a href="https://www.vmware.com/content/vmware/vmware-published-sites/us/products/esxi-and-esx.html.html">ESXi</a> just to get started.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about the reality. Do you have an old  laptop? Maybe an old gaming rig that you recently replaced? Cool! Ignore the rack-mounted server as you&rsquo;re 100% ready to get started.</p>
<p>While Proxmox and ESXi are both awesome and great platforms to build your home lab on, you don&rsquo;t need them to test the waters. Regardless of what platform you&rsquo;re on, you can build VMs with <a href="https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads">VirtualBox</a>, or if you&rsquo;re on Windows (10 or Server) specifically you can use <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualization/hyper-v-on-windows/quick-start/enable-hyper-v">HyperV</a> (<a href="https://www.thedatanewbie.com/2018/04/tutorial-set-up-linux-vm-on-windows.html">which I did a tutorial on a while back</a>. Lastly, you&rsquo;ve got the ability across all of these platforms to play with containerization with <a href="https://www.docker.com/">Docker</a> or <a href="https://kubernetes.io/">Kubernetes</a>.</p>
<p>While we won&rsquo;t dive into the details of each of these technologies here, the point is simply that all of this is already available for you to work with and learn even if it&rsquo;s on a 10 year old Dell desktop you bought from a library!</p>
<p>If you <em>really</em> don&rsquo;t have what you need here, there are tons of trial options with services like Amazon AWS EC2 or the free tier of Google Cloud Platform, not to mention things like partner codes for discounts with companies like <a href="https://www.linode.com/">Linode</a>.</p>
<h1 id="what-does-my-home-lab-look-like">What does my home lab look like?</h1>
<p>Building off of the info above, I don&rsquo;t have an &ldquo;impressive&rdquo; home lab by any stretch, but it still does everything I need. If IaaS isn&rsquo;t your thing, and you don&rsquo;t have a computer to play around with, you can pertty easily build out the same setup I&rsquo;m using for under $500CDN all-in.</p>
<h2 id="my-lab">My &ldquo;lab&rdquo;</h2>
<ul>
<li>CPU - i5 4670k</li>
<li>RAM -  16GB DDR3</li>
<li>Storage - 256GB SSD, 2TB HDD, 2x 1TB HDD (RAID-1)</li>
<li>NAS Storage - NetGear ReadyNAS NV+ w/ 4x 1.5TB HDD (RAID-5)</li>
<li>Router - ASUS RT-N66U</li>
<li>Switch - Unmanaged 8-port Gbit &amp; 24-port 100Mbit switches</li>
</ul>
<p>Yep, this is all old and busted&hellip; and it runs Windows 10.</p>
<p>The CPU is 7 years old, and both the RAM and HDDs were bought used. The NAS is 10 years old and can&rsquo;t handle transfer speeds above 15MB/s despite having a 1Gbit NIC.</p>
<p>But you know what? This setup still does everything I need. You can buy a comparable PC + hard drives for around $350CDN, and I got that NAS with its drives for $100 and a bottle of wine.</p>
<h1 id="what-do-i-use-that-junk-listed-above-to-do">What do I use that junk listed above to do?</h1>
<p>I&rsquo;ll start by noting that I&rsquo;m a hobbyist in this space. I use this setup to tinker and to handle some specific usecases for my home, as well as general learning. I&rsquo;d be pretty happy to recommend this setup for any low(er) level IT certification training, and it&rsquo;s absolutely sufficient as a development/testing environment across a variety of operating systems.</p>
<p>With that out of the way, here&rsquo;s what I&rsquo;m using this setup for:</p>
<ul>
<li>4x Ubuntu Server VMs running under Hyper-V
<ul>
<li>ELK - Collecting system metrics and DNS info from all VMs</li>
<li>Plex - Serving up media content (720p/1080p CPU transcoding)</li>
<li>PiHole - Blocking adds and obnoxious traffic from my network.</li>
<li>Ansible - Configuration management and automating updates across all of my VMs</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2x RHEL VMs for certification training/tinkering</li>
<li>OpenVPN server into my home network</li>
<li>Torrenting &ldquo;Linux ISOs&rdquo;</li>
<li>Securing outgoing network traffic over VPN</li>
<li>NAS
<ul>
<li>Backups from all machines on my network (via OS tooling or rsync)</li>
<li>Media storage (music, video, software, etc.)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>A lot of these use cases are evolving. For example, I set up ELK stack mostly to play around with it and to refresh my knowledge since I&rsquo;d been away from it for a while, but it&rsquo;s not particularly useful for an environment my size outside of tinkering.</p>
<h1 id="how-do-i-keep-track-of-all-these-things">How do I keep track of all these things?</h1>
<p>Fortunately, this is pretty simple to answer. Ansible handles basically everything for me, pulling my configs from my (currently private) GitHub repositories and syncing them across all machines where they&rsquo;re needed.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve got a goal of eventually making all of that public, but want to be sure it doesn&rsquo;t have too much information in it regarding my network/services/configurations.</p>
<h1 id="whats-next-for-my-home-lab">What&rsquo;s next for my home lab?</h1>
<p>As you&rsquo;ve probably guessed, the possibilities here are somewhat endless, but here&rsquo;s a high level overview of what I&rsquo;m looking to do with over the next couple of months/years:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hardware
<ul>
<li>Update my router with a more powerful configuration (e.g. Unifi devices)</li>
<li>Replace my NAS with something more modern (e.g. Synology 4 or 5 bay NAS)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Software/Use cases
<ul>
<li>RTSP server for home security cameras</li>
<li>Replace various VMs with Docker containers to both free up resources and to gain further experience working with Docker</li>
<li>Further automation with Ansible to cover as many software configurations as possible</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="where-can-i-learn-more">Where can I learn more?</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/HomeNetworking/">https://www.reddit.com/r/HomeNetworking/</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Draining the (Big Data) Swamp</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2018-07/draining-the-big-data-swamp/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2018-07/draining-the-big-data-swamp/</guid>
			<description>Before we dive too far into this article, let&amp;rsquo;s define a few key terms that will come up at several points:
 Big Data - Technology relating to the storage, management, and utilization of &amp;ldquo;Big Data&amp;rdquo; (e.g. enormous amounts of data/petabyte scale). Data Lake - A common term to refer to a storage platform for Big Data. In this case, let&amp;rsquo;s assume Apache Hadoop (HDFS) or Amazon S3. Data Warehouse - A large store of data sourced from a variety of sources within a company, then used to guide management or business decisions.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Before we dive too far into this article, let&rsquo;s define a few key terms that will come up at several points:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>Big Data</code> - Technology relating to the storage, management, and utilization of &ldquo;Big Data&rdquo; (e.g. enormous amounts of data/petabyte scale).</li>
<li><code>Data Lake</code> - A common term to refer to a storage platform for Big Data. In this case, let&rsquo;s assume Apache Hadoop (HDFS) or Amazon S3.</li>
<li><code>Data Warehouse</code> - A large store of data sourced from a variety of sources within a company, then used to guide management or business decisions.</li>
<li><code>ETL</code> - Extract, Transform, Load. The process of taking data from one source, making changes to it, and loading it into another location. The underpinning of Master Data Management, and basically all data movement.</li>
<li><code>Master Data Management (MDM)</code> - The concept of merging important data into a single point of reference. For a lot of Big Data applications, this means tying data back to a single person or actor.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="now-with-that-out-of-the-way-why-on-earth-is-the-name-of-this-article-talking-about-a-data-swamp">Now with that out of the way&hellip; why on earth is the name of this article talking about a Data Swamp?</h1>
<p>Coming from the RDBMS/data warehouse world - data normalization and MDM is a critical part of any project involving data. Generally there will be some source system that is feeding data in that is then &ldquo;cleaned&rdquo; (or normalized) to reduce duplication/inconsistencies and is then fed into a data warehouse which is used for reporting.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s say that you&rsquo;re handling data coming in from two ubiquitous Microsoft platforms - Active Directory and Exchange. Both of these have relatively consistent logging formats to track access, or at least to track behaviour, but where things get different quickly is who they say is accessing things.</p>
<p>With Active Directory logs (let&rsquo;s just say evtx format for the sake of argument), you&rsquo;ll see the account name as <code>DOMAIN\User</code>, or in some cases <code>user@domain.com</code>. With Exchange, however, you&rsquo;re going to see data coming in under the user&rsquo;s email address or, if there&rsquo;s no authentication configured, whatever email address was specified as the sender&hellip; in some cases this is going to be <code>user@domain.com</code> however frequently it can also be <code>firstname.lastname@domain.com</code> or any other infinite number of ways that an organization chooses to reference email addresses.</p>
<p>To put this into a more real world example, at a company I used to work with my login for the domain was in the format of a country code and employee ID, e.g. <code>CA123456</code>, so AD would track me under that ID and only that ID. At that same company I had two email addresses - <code>tdn@company.com</code>, and <code>thedatanewbie@company.com</code> (short name and long name). See where this gets confusing!?</p>
<h1 id="ok-now-i-understand-that-data-is-a-mess-whats-your-point">OK, now I understand that data is a mess&hellip; What&rsquo;s your point?</h1>
<p>Now picture yourself on the receiving end of those logs and trying to piece this all together into a working scenario where you can say that I logged in at 8AM at my normal office place and send out fifteen emails to thirty recipients&hellip; That&rsquo;s where MDM comes into play!</p>
<p>Despite the seemingly strange approach, there&rsquo;s usually a method to the madness in this sort of thing. Generally all of these items are referenced together in some place&hellip; generally an Active Directory user profile or some LDAP based equivalent. Easy to use, right!? Maybe&hellip;</p>
<p>Attributes in an LDAP profile can be public, meaning anyone who can do a lookup on the user can see them, or they can be private which means that you have to be authorized to see them. In a lot of cases the public attributes are only going to be group memberships, a real name, and the user name - this leaves a lot out to dry.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s assume, though, that we have privileged access and can now read all the attributes - we&rsquo;ve got our source of truth! Fantastic! Let&rsquo;s ignore the logistics of trying to maintain up to date LDAP lookups on demand for tens of thousands of users, let alone hundreds of thousands, and move on&hellip;</p>
<p>At this point a consulting team that gets paid lots of money is going to implement some sort of ETL pipeline that pulls data from the source system, does enrichment to tie this all to the &ldquo;one true version&rdquo; of a user, and then loads it into the Data Warehouse which will be used for reporting.</p>
<h1 id="this-all-sounds-great-weve-identified-how-to-enrich-the-data-ignoring-the-logistics-of-doing-so-and-now-youve-got-a-data-warehouse-you-can-report-off-of">This all sounds great! We&rsquo;ve identified how to enrich the data (ignoring the logistics of doing so), and now you&rsquo;ve got a Data Warehouse you can report off of!</h1>
<p>Absolutely, it is great, but here is where we get back to the title of this article! Everything I just described is extremely common in the relational database world (e.g. Oracle, MS SQL Server, etc&hellip;) for reporting with products like Cognos, Qlik, etc&hellip; but unfortunately it is a concept that seems to be routinely ignored in the Big Data world.</p>
<p>As noted earlier, a lot of people will take these logs from many places and store them in their Data Lake for future use/analysis/etc&hellip; While it&rsquo;s great that they get stored, what this means is that you&rsquo;ve got likely petabytes worth of data that you&rsquo;re paying to store but are not using for anything and could not effectively use for anything that would not be extremely resource intensive to implement.</p>
<h1 id="this-is-why-big-data-implementations-fail">This is why Big Data implementations fail!</h1>
<p>Big Data is expensive, and its complex&hellip; it&rsquo;s the perfect storm of hard to do! With this said, all of the same concepts we talked about earlier still apply, they just have to be done differently! Running data through an ETL tool designed for an RDBMS that maybe operates on a total of 24 CPU cores and 128GB of RAM isn&rsquo;t going to cut it when you&rsquo;re dealing with enterprise levels of log files.</p>
<p>This is where I say it&rsquo;s expensive - not only do you need to have the expertise and knowledge of which tooling to use and how to use it, you need be willing to pay to make it happen. In a lot of cases for an enterprise handling authentication logs, email logs, endpoint logs, firewall logs, etc&hellip; this is going to be manifesting its self in the many dozens of CPU cores and hundreds of gigabytes of memory just to do the normalization. You can quickly see why there&rsquo;s hesitation to do this - who wants to spend upwards of half a million dollars on something that&rsquo;s just changing a user name in a log file!?</p>
<p>Unfortunately, without spending that money, those logs that are sitting in S3 (despite it being really cheap) are not really going to be useful if you want to use them down the road. This is where you wind up with the eponymous Data Swamp - a very murky lake full of data.</p>
<p>Many Data Lakes get set up as part of security initiatives so that there can be a postmortem on a breach, or even used proactively in the world of UEBA and Security Analytics, but without this MDM work (and in many cases even basic normalization) that company is going to wind up with the following challenges, to name a few:
Weeks or months of time spent identifying the characteristics and &ldquo;shapes&rdquo; of the data that is stored in the data lake.
The same cost that would have been incurred originally to now perform that MDM work (but under a time crunch).
Added costs and stress of trying to expedite an implementation of something to analyze the logs, or to have their security team(s) manually review them in a SIEM style tool like Splunk.
Really, it just circles back to what could have been done in the first place, and what would have allowed that company to have proactive tools in place, but even past that do immediate manual analysis or rules-based analysis of the data that was stored without having to incur all of the additional costs, stress, and time taken to do so after the fact.</p>
<h1 id="youre-painting-a-pretty-dire-picture-are-all-big-data-implementations-like-this">You&rsquo;re painting a pretty dire picture&hellip; Are all Big Data implementations like this?</h1>
<p>NO! Thank goodness they are not, but the ones that fail all seem to have the same characteristics.</p>
<ul>
<li>No willingness to spend (usually this turns into all of this data living in S3 because it&rsquo;s cheap).</li>
<li>Limited forethought into the end use case (e.g. SIEM, Security Analytics, etc&hellip;).</li>
<li>No dedicated team for the platform, and thus no one to enable the end use case.</li>
</ul>
<p>The ones that are successful, however, tend to have done the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Brought in, or hired, the expertise to handle the data movement and transformation, and continue to engage with those teams if they are not permanent.</li>
<li>Implement(ed) the Data Lake with a specific goal in mind, and identified the work required to make that happen.</li>
<li>Engaged with, or at least consulted, vendors that would enable the use case once the data was available.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="lets-wrap-this-up">Let&rsquo;s wrap this up.</h1>
<p>Is this technically easy? Absolutely not. It&rsquo;s not easy even in the RDBMS world where a few dozen gigabytes of sales data across 500 retails stores is considered a huge volume of data to report off of. What I&rsquo;m saying at the end of this is that conceptually it&rsquo;s something that seems to get missed in a lot of Big Data implementations, and there are a lot of folks out there who have been blasting Big Data/Hadoop implementations for years despite the fact that a lot of those issues can be tied back to this at the end of the day.</p>
<p>If this struck a chord with you, and it&rsquo;s something you&rsquo;re having trouble with, keep an eye on this blog and the associated YouTube channel. We&rsquo;re going to be taking a look at a bunch of technology that enables this whole thing to work - Kafka, NiFi, Elasticsearch, Hadoop, etc&hellip; there&rsquo;s no shortage of platforms to let you do this work, and even choosing the &ldquo;wrong&rdquo; one generally won&rsquo;t hamstring you too much, but you have to make that leap to get started!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Being Self-Reliant with Technology</title>
			<link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2018-04/self-reliant/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2018-04/self-reliant/</guid>
			<description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about &amp;ldquo;self-reliance&amp;rdquo; as it relates to career and learning. The three aspects of this we&amp;rsquo;re going to discuss are:
 Research Failure Asking for Help  Research You&amp;rsquo;re sitting at your desk, and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a piece of code that isn&amp;rsquo;t working, or some other challenge&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s not even technical! You&amp;rsquo;re stuck and you&amp;rsquo;ve run out of ideas, so you need to turn somewhere else for answers.
The first instinct of many people in this situation is to simply ask someone else, but I virtually guarantee that others have already done that, and you can likely find your answer on Google!</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about &ldquo;self-reliance&rdquo; as it relates to career and learning. The three aspects of this we&rsquo;re going to discuss are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Research</li>
<li>Failure</li>
<li>Asking for Help</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="research">Research</h1>
<p>You&rsquo;re sitting at your desk, and you&rsquo;ve got a piece of code that isn&rsquo;t working, or some other challenge&hellip; it&rsquo;s not even technical! You&rsquo;re stuck and you&rsquo;ve run out of ideas, so you need to turn somewhere else for answers.</p>
<p>The first instinct of many people in this situation is to simply ask someone else, but I virtually guarantee that others have already done that, and you can likely find your answer on Google! Obvious, right!?</p>
<p>The problem many people encounter when turning to Google (or any form of research like this) is that they will try to be too specific in what they are looking for, and a lot of the time it will result in little to nothing being found. What you can do, instead, is search for variations of your issue - for example, take parts of an error message or the error code so that you can get a broad understanding of what you could be looking at.</p>
<p>For tech purposes, Stack Overflow is a common resource that people will turn to directly, or which will come up in searches. Very frequently, you&rsquo;ll find an answer to your question on Stack Overflow, but it may not be the answer. By this I mean that the solution you find may work, but it may not be the most efficient way to address the problem.</p>
<p>The goal of your research should not only be to find an answer, but to learn from the plethora of information you find so that you can determine the best approach forward.</p>
<h1 id="failure">Failure</h1>
<p>Next up, we&rsquo;re going to about failure.</p>
<p>Isn&rsquo;t this what got us here to start!? Yes, but it&rsquo;s also the best way to learn!</p>
<p>Continuing with the example of some broken code - you&rsquo;ve now done some research, found ten or twenty different ways to code around the problem, and now you need to implement those and find out:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do they work?</li>
<li>Which is the best for your purposes?</li>
<li>What can you change to make it work even better?</li>
</ul>
<p>It may seem intuitive that you want to test your code before using it in the real world, but this meme exists for a reason:</p>
<p><img src="https://msdnshared.blob.core.windows.net/media/MSDNBlogsFS/prod.evol.blogs.msdn.com/CommunityServer.Blogs.Components.WeblogFiles/00/00/01/32/02/metablogapi/8054.image_thumb_35C6E986.png" alt="test in production"></p>
<p>Work in your local (or cloud based) development environment, break things until you find what works best!</p>
<h1 id="asking-for-help">Asking for Help</h1>
<p>We&rsquo;ve done research, and now we&rsquo;ve tried, and failed, to solve the problem. On the plus side, we&rsquo;ve learned a ton about the situation and some ways to address and avoid similar problems in the future, but are still stuck&hellip; it&rsquo;s time to ask for help!</p>
<p>Yes, you could have started out with this, but the reason it&rsquo;s the last step is that the goal here isn&rsquo;t only to solve a problem - it&rsquo;s to learn from solving it. The great part about having done your research, and having tried things, is that you&rsquo;ve not only saved yourself time in the future but you&rsquo;re going to save time for the person you&rsquo;re going to be asking as well.</p>
<p>The first questions that you will get almost every time when asking for help are &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the issue, and what have you tried?&rdquo;.</p>
<p>By having tried many things and researched before involving someone else and using their time, you can answer this with an educated statement around what has not worked, what may have gotten you part of the way toward an answer, and what you think might be the path forward.</p>
<p>Chances are that the person you&rsquo;re asking for help already is going to follow, or already has in their past experience, the exact same steps here. It&rsquo;s due to this experience, that you&rsquo;re now trying to build, that you&rsquo;ll be able to work together to get a quick and good solution.</p>
<h1 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h1>
<p>I know this all seems like it&rsquo;s common sense, but you&rsquo;d be surprised at how many people skip this process and just jump to asking other people - especially skipping the &ldquo;Failure&rdquo; after not finding an exact answer after some preliminary research. At the end of the day, yes, getting your solution was slower than just asking, but think of all of the time that you&rsquo;ve now saved yourself in the future, as well as the time that would have been working through these same steps with someone else.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
