<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>career on Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/tags/career/</link><description>Recent content in career on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maclaren.dev/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>January's woes</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-01/january_woes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-01/january_woes/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s ~Morphin~ Bitchin time! I try to stay pretty positive with this blog, so I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this reasonably short.
The Apple Silicon Macs are amazing performance, battery life, power consumption, etc&amp;hellip; They&amp;rsquo;re also nearly worthless for my usecase as a developer and user of predominantly x86 applications.
Fortunately, most of the Python ecosystem seems to support aarch64 so much of my code works. The problems in Python come when you need something that&amp;rsquo;s x86 native&amp;hellip; like trying to use pwntools.</description></item><item><title>Obligatory look back at 2022</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-12/make_a_ctf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-12/make_a_ctf/</guid><description>In retrospect&amp;hellip; Certainly there has been a fair bit of change for me over the course of 2022. I&amp;hellip;
Found a new hobby (CTF) and continue to build those skills Realized being a people manager wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me Have been involved in tons of engineering projects that I otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a chance to work on Changed career paths (within tech) pretty drastically Joined a great team and have seen its members grow significantly Am exploring multiple new and exciting career and learning opportunities Went on a trip to DEFCON, something I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do for many years Spoke at a security conference, and have submitted to the CFP for others!</description></item><item><title>Management, burnout, and upcoming changes</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-06/changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2022-06/changes/</guid><description>Management I got into management about a year ago, and it has been one hell of a ride. There&amp;rsquo;s sort of a running joke that &amp;ldquo;management isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone&amp;rdquo;, and I can certainly verify that.
I had moved into management with the hopes of it being a great way to advance my career further, push me closer to the goal of getting a Director position, and hopefully scratching the same problem solving itch that solving technical problems and helping organize my team as a lead did.</description></item><item><title>Being Self-Reliant with Technology</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2018-04/self-reliant/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2018-04/self-reliant/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about &amp;ldquo;self-reliance&amp;rdquo; as it relates to career and learning. The three aspects of this we&amp;rsquo;re going to discuss are:
Research Failure Asking for Help Research You&amp;rsquo;re sitting at your desk, and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a piece of code that isn&amp;rsquo;t working, or some other challenge&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s not even technical! You&amp;rsquo;re stuck and you&amp;rsquo;ve run out of ideas, so you need to turn somewhere else for answers.
The first instinct of many people in this situation is to simply ask someone else, but I virtually guarantee that others have already done that, and you can likely find your answer on Google!</description></item></channel></rss>