<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>homelab on Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/tags/homelab/</link><description>Recent content in homelab on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.maclaren.dev/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>State of the Lab (late 2023)</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-12/lab_updates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-12/lab_updates/</guid><description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t you just blog that this was going to be a 2024 project? Or, more specifically, I got a bit too excited after writing the last post and some hardware I was eyeing up went on sale. Since this update is happening today (hopefully) I figured this might be a good time to finally do a full walkthrough of what hardware and services I&amp;rsquo;m running.
The hardware Old &amp;amp; busted As noted, I&amp;rsquo;m finally replacing my venerable home server.</description></item><item><title>2023 in Review - DEFCON, CVEs, and Life</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-12/2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-12/2023/</guid><description>What is time, anyway? 2023 is at an end, and my posts to this blog have been few and far between this year. Fortunately, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a reflection of having a lack of things to do but perhaps the opposite. Please enjoy this highlight reel of &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; things that 2023 has brought&amp;hellip;
I spoke at a few conferences One of my personal goals this year was to submit to a few CFPs (Call for Papers) for various security-related conferences after getting back into public speaking in some capacity with BSides Ottawa in 2022.</description></item><item><title>March Madness</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-03/march_madness/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2023-03/march_madness/</guid><description>Happy pi day!
It has been a minute As someone working in the tech industry right now, let&amp;rsquo;s just say I haven&amp;rsquo;t been in the best frame of mind to blog about stuff, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few ideas for some content here, so maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll all flow out at once 🤷 On an immediately bright note, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been laid off (yet), so things continue to look up!
With that said, this article is going to be upbeat!</description></item><item><title>Home lab updates v2</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2021-11/home_lab_updates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2021-11/home_lab_updates/</guid><description>Looks like the last time I posted any updates about my home lab setup was back in April of 2020, so I guess we&amp;rsquo;re do for an update!
What has changed? Server rebuild New (2nd hand) 24 port gigabit switch 900W UPS Synology DS918 NAS So what am I doing with all these toys? The server rebuild is probably one of the bigger things here. While I was already hosting VMs and Docker containers on this box when it was running Windows, it was unreliable at best thanks to forced updates/reboots in Windows 10.</description></item><item><title>Server Rebuild</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2021-05/server_rebuild/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2021-05/server_rebuild/</guid><description>What did I do? Half fueled by beer, and half by a playlist of keygen tracks, I decided that it would be a good idea to finally getting around to rebuilding my long-lived server&amp;hellip; No more Windows and its infuriating forced updates (which you used to be able to override), lack of clear/consistent OS level event scripting for integration with my UPS, or garbage-tier support from Docker. I wanted something that I&amp;rsquo;d finally have the level of control I wanted for something that backs pretty much eveverything I use outside of work.</description></item><item><title>Home lab updates</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</guid><description>Following up from my &amp;ldquo;Starting out with a home lab&amp;rdquo; article I&amp;rsquo;ve made some pretty nice updates to my home lab setup, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also got my {Ansible playbooks](https://github.com/maclarel/ansible_playbooks) up on GitHub now!
Starting out with the lab additions:
Gigabit internet (Cable, unfortunately) recently became available here, so I&amp;rsquo;ve now got a 1000/30 connection! Upload speeds are depressing, but still 3x the speed I had previously! UniFi Dream Machine has taken over my network.</description></item><item><title>Starting out with a home lab</title><link>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2020-04/starting-out-with-a-home-lab/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.maclaren.dev/posts/2020-04/starting-out-with-a-home-lab/</guid><description>Why do I want a home lab? While only you, the reader, can answer this, there are many reasons that I&amp;rsquo;ve build one out. I imagine your reasoning will be similar.
There are things you want to have, or automate, that are simply obnoxious otherwise. You&amp;rsquo;ve got specific technologies that you want to explore without a full scale investment. You&amp;rsquo;re working toward certifications (or hands-on experience) with technologies that you want to be using for work.</description></item></channel></rss>