<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ctf on Logan MacLaren</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/tags/ctf/</link><description>Recent content in ctf on Logan MacLaren</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maclarel.github.io/tags/ctf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hack The Box - Toxic</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-09/htb_toxic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-09/htb_toxic/</guid><description>Premise Toxic is another whitebox Web challenge from HackTheBox, and presents itself as a web page about the Dart Frog. The goal here is to find a way to retrieve the flag from the web server, using what appears to be a non-interactive webpage.
Captain Crunch hurts my mouth Since this is a whitebox challenge, we&amp;rsquo;re given the source code to review, and a local container that we can play with if so inclined.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - PetPetRcbee</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-09/htb_petpetrcbee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-09/htb_petpetrcbee/</guid><description>Premise PetPetRcbee is a Web challenge from Hack The Box that presents itself as a website which will take an image and animate it. Unlike many other challenges, you may be able to solve this one without ever actually looking at the site or seeing how it works&amp;hellip;
The setup This is a Flask application using Pillow and Ghostscript (9.23 - remember this) as the basis for its functionality. The overall source code is quite minimal, so review is easy.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - RedPanda</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-08/htb_redpanda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-08/htb_redpanda/</guid><description>Premise RedPanda is a machine challenge that presents the attacker with a web app displaying cute pictures of Red Pandas. Adorable. The goal, as usual, is to find both user and root flags. This is done through a combination of SSTI and XXE, and admittedly is one of the most difficult challenges that I&amp;rsquo;ve completed so far&amp;hellip; despite being on the &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; end of the spectrum.
Notes in this writeup will be a bit more freeform than others as I think sharing the overall approach I took may be of interest.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - Phonebook</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-08/htb_phonebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-08/htb_phonebook/</guid><description>Premise Phonebook is a Web challenge from Hack The Box that presents us with a login page for a &amp;ldquo;phonebook&amp;rdquo; system. The goal here is to find a flag hidden somewhere, however it&amp;rsquo;s considerably less obvious than it may seem.
Exploration When first navigating to the challenge URL you&amp;rsquo;l be greeted with a login prompt to access the phonebook. There don&amp;rsquo;t appear to be any useful links here, however there&amp;rsquo;s a note that the system now supports &amp;ldquo;workstation logins&amp;rdquo; and that post is signed by someone called &amp;ldquo;Reese&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>HackTheBox - Cyber Apocalypse 2022</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-05/htb_cyber_apolcalypse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-05/htb_cyber_apolcalypse/</guid><description>Well, that was harder than expected Many times in life it&amp;rsquo;s great to have a humbling experience. Not that I had an ego in this space anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m super new to it, but I was going in expecting to be able to crank through a fair number of challenges for this event. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say that didn&amp;rsquo;t happen.
Cyber Apocalypse 2022 was a jeopardy style CTF event with categories across all of the usual HackTheBox challenge content.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Strike CTF 2022 - Contoso Financial</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/msft_contoso_strike/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/msft_contoso_strike/</guid><description>Premise Microsoft runs an internal CTF event every so often called Strike CTF. While we&amp;rsquo;ve been asked not to share specifics around the challenges involved, I wanted to do a brief write-up, as it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a unique one that catered to multiple skill levels and had an educational twist.
For anyone interested in doing some digging, the version Microsoft runs has also been seen in some B-Sides events (and other conferences) under the name ShadowBank.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - Pandora</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/htb_pandora/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/htb_pandora/</guid><description>Premise Second verse same as the first - we&amp;rsquo;re given an IP and no further information. Commence enumeration!
Enumeration To set the stage, enumeration is probably the hardest part of this challenge. The rest is doable with some patience and research.
Out of the gate we have a website talking about some random product. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing interactable, and nmap only gives us TCP 22 and 80 as open ports.
Fuzzing with ffuf and nikto turns up nothing actionable, just icons and asset directories, neither of which can be used for anything.</description></item><item><title>Hack The Box - Paper</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/htb_paper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-04/htb_paper/</guid><description>Premise As with all Hack The Box (HTB) Machines we&amp;rsquo;re given nothing more than an IP.
Initial target enumeration with nmap shows us TCP 22, 80, and 443 open, with SSH and Apache 2.4.37 respectively. The TLS information returned isn&amp;rsquo;t super helpful, and hitting the website gives us nothing more than the default CentOS Apache httpd page.
Further exploration Next step, after a lot of poking, prodding, fuzzing, etc&amp;hellip; and getting nowhere was to try out nikto to see if there&amp;rsquo;s anything else the webserver might be leaking for us.</description></item><item><title>picoCTF - notepad</title><link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-03/pico_notepad/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2022-03/pico_notepad/</guid><description>Premise We&amp;rsquo;re given a service that will take abitrary input, and render it as an HTML page.
There are a few restrictions:
Content cannot be longer than 512 characters Content cannot include _ or / characters Lastly, from the Dockerfile we know that the flag is going to have an arbtirary name starting with flag-.
Examining the tarball This challenge comes with a tarball that contains the source code so we can do some white box analysis of how all of this works.</description></item></channel></rss>