<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logan MacLaren</title>
    <link>https://maclarel.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Logan MacLaren</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maclarel.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I use Arch, btw</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-10/arch_btw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-10/arch_btw/</guid>
      <description>I use Arch, btw I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux for ages, nearly two decades at this point. I actually dug out my old Mandrake and Slackware CDs while going through a box in my basement the other day&amp;hellip; quite the flashback.
Despite that tenure on at least some of the hardware I&amp;rsquo;ve owned at any given time, I&amp;rsquo;ve never really used it as a daily driver for desktop usage. That changed today when I finally sat down and set up Arch, complete with forgetting to install a boot loader, on my main rig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Rebuild</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-05/server_rebuild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-05/server_rebuild/</guid>
      <description>What did I do? Half fueled by beer, and half by a playlist of keygen tracks, I decided that it would be a good idea to finally getting around to rebuilding my long-lived server&amp;hellip; No more Windows and its infuriating forced updates (which you used to be able to override), lack of clear/consistent OS level event scripting for integration with my UPS, or garbage-tier support from Docker. I wanted something that I&amp;rsquo;d finally have the level of control I wanted for something that backs pretty much eveverything I use outside of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard ascension</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-05/keebs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-05/keebs/</guid>
      <description>Keebs Mechanical keyboards, sometimes calld keebs, come up from time to time as a bit of a meme. &amp;ldquo;Oh, you&amp;rsquo;ve got one of those loud keyboards.&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Why on earth did you spend $500 ona a keyboard that does the same thing as the $5 one I got from Office Depot?&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ll say that, for the really cheap end of the spectrum with mechanical keyboards, this really is a meme that holds up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello via GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-01/github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-01/github-pages/</guid>
      <description>Well this is new&amp;hellip; Rather than dealing with Blogger, a dubious mobile interface, and spreading things across many services&amp;hellip; why not just use GitHub Pages? I&amp;rsquo;m so used to writing markdown at this point that it just seems easier 😄
Hugo Inspired by tmpdubz I figured I&amp;rsquo;d do a double-whammy here - play around with/learn GitHub Pages, while also giving my blog a much needed cosmetic overhaul/simplification/rebranding. This lead to Hugo, which is pretty darn neat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git &amp; GitHub Tutorial - Part 2 - Branching, forking, and pull requests</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-08/github-tutorial-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-08/github-tutorial-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is part 2 of a Git tutorial series - I recommend watching part 1 @ https://youtu.be/jhgoGnYgPuY first!
In this video we take a look at creating new branches in a Git repository, forking other repositories, and creating pull requests:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git &amp; GitHub Tutorial - Part 1 - Creating &amp; using a Git repository</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/github-tutorial-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/github-tutorial-part-1/</guid>
      <description>In this video we start to delve into using Git and GitHub to track a project. We will create a repository, clone it, make changes, and push those changes back up to GitHub so that everyone can view them!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key-based Authentication for SSH</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/key-based-auth-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/key-based-auth-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Tired of trying to remember passwords for every system you access, or annoyed that every system uses the same password? Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a more secure approach that can solve both problems - key based authentication with SSH!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Port Forwarding</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/ssh-port-forwarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/ssh-port-forwarding/</guid>
      <description>Have a service that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to directly expose, or that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have good security, that you still need to access? Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at using SSH to accomplish this!
This tutorial uses nc, UFW/IPTables, and SSH to demonstrate how to forward any port over an SSH connection on TCP 22. You can extend this to just about any service. For example, this works for accessing websites, or other services that are exposed through a web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Office Tour</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/home-office-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/home-office-tour/</guid>
      <description>A quick tour of my full time work-from-home office! I&amp;rsquo;ve been working remote for many years now, and for the past ~18 months I&amp;rsquo;ve been working from home almost exclusively (no more travel).
This is a quick look over the setup that I use every day!
Equipment shown:
 Desk: Jarvis Standing Desk Monitor: LG 38UC99-W Monitor Arm: Amazon Basics Premium Mouse: Logitech MX Master Keyboard: Das Keyboard 4C Professional (MX Brown) Laptop Stand: Rain Design mStand Dock: CalDigit TS3 Plus Chair: HÅG Capisco Puls Standing mat: Ergodriven Topo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home lab updates</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</guid>
      <description>Following up from my &amp;ldquo;Starting out with a home lab&amp;rdquo; article I&amp;rsquo;ve made some pretty nice updates to my home lab setup, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also got my {Ansible playbooks](https://github.com/maclarel/ansible_playbooks) up on GitHub now!
Starting out with the lab additions:
 Gigabit internet (Cable, unfortunately) recently became available here, so I&amp;rsquo;ve now got a 1000/30 connection! Upload speeds are depressing, but still 3x the speed I had previously! UniFi Dream Machine has taken over my network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
