<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Logan MacLaren</title>
    <link>https://maclarel.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Logan MacLaren</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maclarel.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-01/helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-01/helloworld/</guid>
      <description>Hello World Is anyone out there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Office Tour</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/home-office-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/home-office-tour/</guid>
      <description>A quick tour of my full time work-from-home office! I&amp;rsquo;ve been working remote for many years now, and for the past ~18 months I&amp;rsquo;ve been working from home almost exclusively (no more travel).
This is a quick look over the setup that I use every day!
Equipment shown:
 Desk: Jarvis Standing Desk Monitor: LG 38UC99-W Monitor Arm: Amazon Basics Premium Mouse: Logitech MX Master Keyboard: Das Keyboard 4C Professional (MX Brown) Laptop Stand: Rain Design mStand Dock: CalDigit TS3 Plus Chair: HÅG Capisco Puls Standing mat: Ergodriven Topo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home lab updates</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</guid>
      <description>Following up from my &amp;ldquo;Starting out with a home lab&amp;rdquo; article I&amp;rsquo;ve made some pretty nice updates to my home lab setup, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also got my {Ansible playbooks](https://github.com/maclarel/ansible_playbooks) up on GitHub now!
Starting out with the lab additions:
 Gigabit internet (Cable, unfortunately) recently became available here, so I&amp;rsquo;ve now got a 1000/30 connection! Upload speeds are depressing, but still 3x the speed I had previously! UniFi Dream Machine has taken over my network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Written communication for support</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/written-communication-for-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/written-communication-for-support/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working in customer facing roles for quite a while now. Granted, these have largely had the luxury of being in software companies, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also done a brief retail stint and I&amp;rsquo;d like to think the same skills apply in all cases.
While this will be by no means exhaustive, I want to go over two high-level concepts that I feel are extremely important, and can sometimes be overlooked even by veterans in customer facing positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting out with a home lab</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/starting-out-with-a-home-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/starting-out-with-a-home-lab/</guid>
      <description>Why do I want a home lab? While only you, the reader, can answer this, there are many reasons that I&amp;rsquo;ve build one out. I imagine your reasoning will be similar.
 There are things you want to have, or automate, that are simply obnoxious otherwise. You&amp;rsquo;ve got specific technologies that you want to explore without a full scale investment. You&amp;rsquo;re working toward certifications (or hands-on experience) with technologies that you want to be using for work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draining the (Big Data) Swamp</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2018-07/draining-the-big-data-swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2018-07/draining-the-big-data-swamp/</guid>
      <description>Before we dive too far into this article, let&amp;rsquo;s define a few key terms that will come up at several points:
 Big Data - Technology relating to the storage, management, and utilization of &amp;ldquo;Big Data&amp;rdquo; (e.g. enormous amounts of data/petabyte scale). Data Lake - A common term to refer to a storage platform for Big Data. In this case, let&amp;rsquo;s assume Apache Hadoop (HDFS) or Amazon S3. Data Warehouse - A large store of data sourced from a variety of sources within a company, then used to guide management or business decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/about-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/about-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is the world’s fastest framework for building websites. It is written in Go.
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 https://github.com/russross/blackfriday https://github.com/alecthomas/chroma https://github.com/muesli/smartcrop https://github.com/spf13/cobra https://github.com/spf13/viper  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
