<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Logan MacLaren</title>
    <link>https://maclarel.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Logan MacLaren</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maclarel.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I still use Arch, btw</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/still_use_arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-11/still_use_arch/</guid>
      <description>Yep, the meme lives on. Still getting by with Arch as a daily driver. Still running it through VirtualBox.
What&amp;rsquo;s great? Full control, and amazingly lightweight. Booted, and with my WM (i3) running, I&amp;rsquo;m measuring &amp;lt; 300MB of RAM usage and virtually zero CPU/disk usage. Windows or Mac OS sitting idle&amp;hellip; yeah, not comparable. Itg&amp;rsquo;s very refreshing having full control over just about every aspect of what I want.
I&amp;rsquo;m getting so used to using i3, with only extremly minor modifications to bindings, that I&amp;rsquo;ve actually updated a lot of my Amethyst bindings to align with i3 defaults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I use Arch, btw</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-10/arch_btw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2021-10/arch_btw/</guid>
      <description>I use Arch, btw I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux for ages, nearly two decades at this point. I actually dug out my old Mandrake and Slackware CDs while going through a box in my basement the other day&amp;hellip; quite the flashback.
Despite that tenure on at least some of the hardware I&amp;rsquo;ve owned at any given time, I&amp;rsquo;ve never really used it as a daily driver for desktop usage. That changed today when I finally sat down and set up Arch, complete with forgetting to install a boot loader, on my main rig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key-based Authentication for SSH</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/key-based-auth-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/key-based-auth-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Tired of trying to remember passwords for every system you access, or annoyed that every system uses the same password? Let&amp;rsquo;s look at a more secure approach that can solve both problems - key based authentication with SSH!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Port Forwarding</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/ssh-port-forwarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-07/ssh-port-forwarding/</guid>
      <description>Have a service that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to directly expose, or that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have good security, that you still need to access? Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at using SSH to accomplish this!
This tutorial uses nc, UFW/IPTables, and SSH to demonstrate how to forward any port over an SSH connection on TCP 22. You can extend this to just about any service. For example, this works for accessing websites, or other services that are exposed through a web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home lab updates</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/home-lab-updates/</guid>
      <description>Following up from my &amp;ldquo;Starting out with a home lab&amp;rdquo; article I&amp;rsquo;ve made some pretty nice updates to my home lab setup, and I&amp;rsquo;ve also got my {Ansible playbooks](https://github.com/maclarel/ansible_playbooks) up on GitHub now!
Starting out with the lab additions:
 Gigabit internet (Cable, unfortunately) recently became available here, so I&amp;rsquo;ve now got a 1000/30 connection! Upload speeds are depressing, but still 3x the speed I had previously! UniFi Dream Machine has taken over my network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting out with a home lab</title>
      <link>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/starting-out-with-a-home-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maclarel.github.io/posts/2020-04/starting-out-with-a-home-lab/</guid>
      <description>Why do I want a home lab? While only you, the reader, can answer this, there are many reasons that I&amp;rsquo;ve build one out. I imagine your reasoning will be similar.
 There are things you want to have, or automate, that are simply obnoxious otherwise. You&amp;rsquo;ve got specific technologies that you want to explore without a full scale investment. You&amp;rsquo;re working toward certifications (or hands-on experience) with technologies that you want to be using for work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
